Welcome to Essential Hayek
欢迎来到哈耶克简要
I'm Don Boudreaux
我是Don Boudreaux
professor of economics at George Mason University
乔治梅森大学经济学教授
senior fellow with the Fraser Institute
弗雷泽研究所高级研究员
and blogger at Café Hayek
博客Café Hayek的博主之一
This video was part of the Fraser Institute initiative
本视频是由弗雷泽研究所制作的
to present the key ideas of F.A. Hayek in an easily accessible format
对哈耶克关键思想的通俗介绍
In this video, we explore Hayek's work on economic booms and busts
本视频将介绍哈耶克对经济繁荣和衰退的研究
work for which he was awarded a Nobel prize in economics in 1974
哈耶克因此研究获得了1974年诺贝尔经济学奖
One of Hayek's key observations was that when government interfering the economy
哈耶克的一个关键发现是政府对经济的干预
it results in people acting in ways that are not sustainable
会导致人们以不可持续的方式行动
which ultimately leads to booms and then, inevitably, busts
这将产生经济的短期繁荣和之后不可避免的萧条
Let's simplify this idea with an example
让我们举个栗子来简化下这个想法
This is Brian
这是Brian
Brian is a politician who thinks he has a great idea for creating jobs and widespread prosperity
他觉得自己有了一个能制造就业并创造广泛繁荣的好想法
With the best intentions
怀着最大的好意
Brian convinces his government to support companies
Brian说服政府支持企业
so that they can develop and build factories to sell chocolate-covered pickles
以让它们建造生产巧克力裹酸黄瓜的工厂
but Brian's plan is flawed
但是Brian的计划是有缺陷的
he assumes there will be great demand for chocolate-covered pickles
他以为对巧克力裹酸黄瓜的需求将会很大
but if they're truly with great demand for chocolate-covered pickles
但假如真有大量的需求
the pickle industry will naturally respond
酸黄瓜制造业自然会做出反应
and build factories of covered pickles with chocolate
去建设巧克力裹酸黄瓜工厂
All without the government assistance
这一切都无需政府帮助
so what happens when there is no real demand by customers for chocolate-covered pickles
所以假如消费者其实并不需要巧克力裹酸黄瓜，那将会怎样？
the resources provided by the government
那样的话，政府提供的资源
whether in the form of direct support like subsidies
如直接的经济补贴
or indirect support like loan guarantees
或间接的贷款担保
distorts the economy by encouraging people to make bad decisions
都会诱使人们做出错误的决策从而扭曲经济
In this case
在这个例子中
to use resources to make chocolate-covered pickles
错误决策指的就是调用资源去生产无人需要的巧克力裹酸黄瓜
As the lack of demand for these pickles becomes apparent
当人们意识到对巧克力裹酸黄瓜的需求其实并不存在时
businesses must adjust by retooling
企业就必须重组
or even scuttling factories
甚至关闭工厂
adjusting their production lines
调整生产线
changing their distribution networks, et cetera
改变分销渠道等等
All of these things mean idle resources in the short term
这些都意味着在经济体自我调整以适应市场的这段时期
as businesses adjust to the reality of the market
会产生资源的短期闲置
The challenge is to ensure that producers
经济正确运行的难处就在于如何让生产者
have the knowledge and the incentives to
获得正确的信息和激励
produce goods and services that people want
去生产人们需要的产品和服务
Government interference, such as through subsidies
政府干预，例如补贴
or specially importantly, by manipulating the money supply
或者影响更大的货币供应调节
obscure that knowledge by distorting prices
扭曲了价格从而模糊了传递给生产者的信息
This interference
这种政府干预
by initially causing producers to tool up
先会导致厂家升级设备
to produce things that consumers don't really want
去生产消费者其实并不需要的产品
inevitably results in producers having to tool down and readjust
然后不可避免地废弃设备、重新调整
in order to better meet true consumer demands
以适应消费者的真实需求
The core insight from Hayek on economic booms and busts
哈耶克对于经济周期的核心观点在于
is that government interference, even when done with the best intentions
即使是抱有最大好意的政府干预
changes people's behavior by changing incentives and changing signals in the market
也会因为改变了市场上的激励和信号而改变人们的行为
These changes result in investments that are not sustainable
这些改变会导致不可持续的投资
and which automatically leads to recessions, or busts
进而导致经济衰退
To learn more and to download  for free
想要下载和更多了解《哈耶克简要》
visit www.essentialhayek.org
请访问www.essentialhayek.org
翻译 by tcya